Fairfax, VA 22031 (818) 671-8222 christopherdenq@gmail.com

CHRISTOPHER DENO

cdenq.github.io github.com/cdenq linkedin.com/in/christopherdenq

SUMMARY

Experience with full-stack software development, database engineering, machine learning, and data analytics. Unique background in art market confers drive to understand topics holistically, strong prioritization of product sense, and ample work-experience on diverse teams. Avid selflearner and serial project-builder who strives to constantly grow, empower others, and add value to the community.

EDUCATION

Foothill College

Los Altos Hills, CA

Associates of Science in Computer Science and Mathematics

April 2022 – September 2022

- **Honors:** Business Innovation Challenge, 2022 (\$500 for risk prediction ML prototype)
- Course Topics: OOP Programming, Cloud Computing, Statistics/Probability, Multivariate Calculus

University of Pennsylvania, College of Arts and Sciences

Bootcamp Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization

Bachelor of Arts, Double Major in Philosophy and Art History

Philadelphia, PA

September 2021 – March 2022

August 2015 – May 2021

- Honors: John C. Parker Fellowship, 2016 (\$500 for statistical research in game theory model)
- Course Topics: Fullstack Software Development, Server Deployment, Database Engineering/Pipelines, Machine Learning, Data Analytics

SKILLS AND FRAMEWORKS

Languages: Python (OOP), Java, SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), HTML/CSS/JS, Git

Libraries/Frameworks: SQLAlchemy, Pymongo, Flask, Jinja, APIs, web-scraping

DevOps & Cloud: Amazon AWS, Docker, Github Pages, Google Collab, Google GCP, Microsoft Azure

Peripheral Technologies: Machine Learning (SKLearn, Hadoop), Data Viz (Tableau, Excel/VBA, Microsoft Office Products)

SELECTED PROJECTS / SELF LEARNING (More on GitHub)

Full-Stack Machine Learning Web-App: Mushroom Edibility Predictor

March 2022

Python (SKLearn, Flask, Matplotlib), HTML/CSS/JS

github.com/cdenq/mushroom-edibility-predictor-web-app

- Full-stack web app that utilizes mushroom data to predict edibility of mushrooms with user inputted features
- Trained 7 ML models on 60k+ data points to predict its edibility to within 80-99% accuracy, created 8 EDA graphs

Full-Stack Interactive Web Dashboard: Market Metrics on Video Game Industry

January 2022

Python (BS4, Flask, Matplotlib), MongoDB, HTML/CSS/JS (Plotly, Leaflet)

github.com/cdeng/web-dashboard-of-video-game-industry

- Full-stack web app that scraped market metrics on the video game industry and dynamically visualizes based on user input
- Analyzed 10k data points, maintained 5 MongoDB collections, created 19 visualizations

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

PNC Financial Services Group Data / Business Analyst Intern

Harrisburg, PA

June 2022 - August 2022

- Contributes to 4+ internal PNC teams across 6 software and data projects to metricize, optimize, and forecast team performance
- Initiative in scaling-and-automation by introducing Python software prototypes to predominantly SQL-driven team
- Attends meetings to understand data requirements, writes efficient SQL to query on-scale, and automates generation of Tableau dashboards

California State University: Northridge, College of Engineering and Computer Science

Northridge, CA

Machine Learning Research Assistant (Internship)

November 2021 – May 2022

- Researched graduate-level ML material, edited/created 280+ class slides, 10+ Java-to-Python code conversion samples
- Succeeded in collaborating, designing, and coding for graduate-level ML course curriculum with Professor Wen-chin Hsu

2U - Trilogy Education Services, Wyzant.com, Local

Various

Teaching Assistant and Tutor for Fullstack Coding Programs, Wyzant AP Computer Science Instructor, Volunteer Tutor September 2021 - Present

- Teach computer science to 25+ students for 65+ hours in 3+ settings: as TA with 2U bootcamps, freelance instructor, and volunteer tutor
- Succeeding in clearly communicating abstract ideas, listening well to understand students' problems, and adapting teaching style

Christie's Auctions & Private Sales

New York, NY

Gallery Intern/Student

June 2020 - August 2020

- Contributed to 6+ reports, appraisals, and collection package documentation; attended 3+ onsite auctions, hilling meetings
- Succeeded in helping Christie's adjust to accelerated digital marketplace and understand its market role amidst pandemic

Oasis Commissary (Non-Profit), University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, PA

Founder and Executive Business Operations Manager

September 2016 – March 2020

- Started non-profit to address local community issue in dorm; wrote grant proposal to Dean, obtained vendor license from Philadelphia city
- Start-up succeeded and absorbed by Penn University; managed 21 staff, 2 managers, \$2000 bi-monthly budget, 6 marketing campaigns
- Succeeded in initiating own business development education, serving college dorm 3 years: \$1300 gross, 22k purchases, 180 unique clients

HOBBIES